Previously on
Space Brothers
むった
＜不運に縁がある兄･六太と➡
Older brother Mutta is plagued by bad luck.
And his younger brother Hibito, born under a lucky star,
ひびと
栄光の日 生まれの弟･日々人＞
is left struggling on the sidelines after a lunar accident, suffering from a panic disorder.
＜月面での事故の影響で
パニック障害となった日々人は➡
前線から外されたものの
復帰試験に なんとか合格！＞
But he's able to pass a test to return to active duty.
＜そして 日々人の遥か後ろから
月を目指し始めた兄･六太は➡
Older brother Mutta continues his long quest to the moon,
ついに月のミッションの
バックアップクルーに任命され➡
having finally been selected as a
backup member for a lunar mission.
訓練に突入した｡一方 ケンジや
にった
新田は月に行けないという➡
And he's about to begin training for the moon.
Meanwhile, Kenji and Nitta have learned they won't be going to the moon,
ことだけが確かな中
日々の訓練を続けていた＞
as they continue to train every day.
Great Baby Names
(ケンジ)う～ん 迷うな｡
Not sure what I want...
やっぱり これからも ほとんど
ヒュｰストンで過ごすわけだから➡
We'll be living in Houston for a while,
アメリカ人でも
発音しやすい名前がいいよね｡
so we should pick a name that's easy for Americans to pronounce.
Yeah, that's true.
(ケンジ)う～ん そうだね｡
ふうか
なあ 風佳｡
Hey, Fuuka...
赤ちゃんの名前 何がいい？
What should we name the baby?
あんちゃん！
An!
あんちゃん？
An?
あん…真壁あん｡
An... Makabe An.
That's cute!
かわいいね！
なんで あんちゃんなの？
Why An?
あんちゃ～ん お姉ちゃんですよ｡
あんちゃ～ん｡
An, I'm your sister.
Ankoro and Me
Author:     Yauchi Mayako
An!
I can't get lost in what I'm doing, nothing works out
I don't want these endlessly dull days
I hope I can move on
before the call of freedom drags me away
What's your wish?
I just want some real courage
We all stare doubt in the face, every one of us
Isn't the unpredictability of life the fun of it?
Devote your life to that dream you can't express
Let's go, advance against the wind, our road is long
Embrace the pain of it too
Take a big breath now, and yell
Big Bang! Chase it without fear!
I want to dream so badly it amazes me
There's cowardice in the way of your true wish
Rip that hot veil aside
#96 Astronaut and Father
Will you be home late again?
今日も帰り 遅くなる？
Yeah,
うん ロシア語での
宇宙機操作試験が近いからね｡
I have a spacecraft-operation test in Russian coming up.
今日も新田君と残って ロシア語で
シミュレーションやるんだよ｡
(ユキ)そう｡
Nitta and I will be staying late to run Russian simulations.
Okay.
あっ でも２３日から
クリスマス休暇は もらえるから｡
But starting the 23rd, I'll be on Christmas break.
ハー ホウ｡
もし陣痛が来たら知らせるんだよ｡
すぐ向かうからね｡
If you start having contractions, let me know.
I'll come running.
オッケー いってらっしゃい｡
Okay, be careful.
ああ…いってきます｡
Yeah.
I'm off.
ウフフ｡
Brighty bright bright!
まっぶしいね～
あっさだよ～
Morning, An! Time to wakey up.
《朝イチは風佳を幼稚園へ送る｡➡
Every morning, I take Fuuka to her preschool.
送ることが せめてもの父らしさの
ような…そんな毎日だ》
It's my one chance every day to act like a father...
(風佳)♪～ はっじめましての
あっさだよ～
Nice to meet you. Time to wakey up.
An! An!
(ケンジ)よろしくお願いしま～す｡
Thank you.
ハーイ グッモーニン フウカ｡
Hi! Good morning, Fuuka.
Good morning.
グッモーニン｡
今度のおゆうぎ会で
やるダンス➡
Today, we'll be practicing the dance for the upcoming recital.
今日から みんなで
練習するからね｡
Uh-huh! Yay!
うん！やった～！
She's fitting in great.
《だいぶ なじんでるな》
ニーモ
《この前のＮＥＥＭＯ訓練には
月面での生活やミッションを➡
In NEEMO training, we had a clear objective,
as we were simulating life on the moon, and the missions we would undertake.
シミュレーションするという
ハッキリした目的があった｡➡
でも月面に行ける可能性は消え➡
But now that we can no longer go the moon, there isn't a clear objective.
何もかもがハッキリしない》
(ｽﾀｯﾌ)今日は新型の宇宙機を
君たちに操作してもらおう｡
Today, you'll be operating a new spacecraft.
操作の具合やディスプレイの
見え方なんかについて➡
We want to hear what astronauts have to say about the controls and the display.
君たち宇宙飛行士の意見も
聞かせて欲しい｡➡
グループごとに評価をして
レポートを提出してくれ｡
Each group will need to submit a report.
切り替えの早さは？
(新田)ＯＫだな｡
How long did the switchover take?
Not too long.
ようし 次だ｡
Okay, on to the next one.
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)《ＮＡＳＡの機密もれ防止の
ためでもあるのか➡
I don't know if it's because NASA's trying to protect its secrets,
宇宙飛行士にさえ すぐに
伝えられない情報があった｡➡
but a lot of information isn't passed on to astronauts.
何を目指しているのかも
あいまいなまま➡
We continue to train as instructed,
僕らは ひたすら
言われた訓練を続けた》
not knowing what we're training for...
(ﾌｨﾘｯﾌﾟ)♪～ ブッブッブ…
なんば
《帰ってきたぜ｡➡
We're back...
ただいま！ヒューストン》
I'm home, Houston.
えっ ダンス？
Huh? A dance?
そうなんですよ！
カントリーダンスですって！
That's right... It's a country dance!
《ハァァ…》
《あ～ 久しぶりのせりかさんに
心が洗われる～》
After seeing Serika again, I feel cleansed...
ダンス教室の先生たちも
事前に来てくれて➡
Some dance instructors will arrive early for an hour-long lecture.
１時間ほどレクチャー
してくれるんですって｡
飛行士も希望者は
参加できるんです｡
If we want, we can participate.
Wait, what?
えっえっ じゃあ せりかさんも？
Are you going, Serika?
えな
ええ！私も絵名ちゃんも
踊りますよ｡
Yes, Ena and I will be dancing.
(北村)うん！楽しみよね｡
南波さんも一緒に どうですか？
I can't wait.
Why don't you join us?
⦅クイック クイック スロー⦆
Quick, quick, slow...
《ああ…》
I s-s-sure will!
やります！やります！
これ基本のステップ？
Are these the basic steps?
Okay! I'll have them memorized in a day!
よ～し！１日で覚えてくるよ｡
ヤッホーウ！
Yahoo!
クイック クイック スロー
クイッ クイック スロー｡
Quick, quick, slow.
クイック クイック スロー｡
クイッ…｡
やあ ムッ君！おかえり！
Quick—
Yo, Mu! Welcome back.
あ～ ケンジ君！
ああ そうだ ケンジ➡
Oh, Kenji!
Right, Kenji.
実は 今度の…｡
ああ ムッ君 ごめん｡
About the...
Mu, sorry...
久しぶりで
色々話したいんだけど➡
I'd love to catch up,
ちょっと今 急いでて｡
あれ？そうなの｡
but I'm in a hurry right now.
Oh, really?
Let's talk later.
また今度 ゆっくり！
O-Okay... Roo-ra!
おおう かぺ～｡
《立派だな みんな 立派だ》
They're all amazing...
Everyone... They're amazing.
《これ…》
Did she make this?
《作ったのか》
ただいま～｡
I'm home.
《さすがに もう寝てるよな》
By now, they must be asleep.
《宇宙飛行士であり 父であり➡
I'm an astronaut and a father.
そんな理想を
手に入れたというのに➡
Both dreams have been achieved...
ずっと｢ふりだし｣にいるような
ゴールの見えない➡
Still, it feels like treading water or acting without a goal.
不安なくらしが続いている｡➡
宇宙飛行士であり 父であり➡
I'm an astronaut and a father.
結局 どっちも未熟なまま
月日ばかりが流れていく》
But time continues to pass without my doing a proper job at either.
(新田)なんちゅう顔してやがんだ
南波のヤツ｡
See the look on Nanba's face?
俺らも この後の課題がなきゃ
存分に楽しめるんだけどな｡
If we didn't have another assignment, we could enjoy ourselves...
No kidding, I could use the rest.
ホント 今日ぐらい休みたいよね｡
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)２人揃ってるな｡
I was looking for both of you.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)ちょうどいい｡
This is perfect.
バトラー室長｡
Chief Butler...
２人に話があるんだが…➡
I need to talk to both of you.
外の空気でも吸いながら どうだ？
Why don't we get some fresh air?
(ユキ)予定日は２週間後ぐらい｡➡
I'm due in two weeks.
あ そうそう こっちにも
日本人がやってる➡
Yes, that's right.
We found an OB/GYN run by someone Japanese.
産婦人科があったんだよ｡
うん よかったよ ほんと｡➡
Yep, it all worked out.
２人目も自然分娩がいいと
思ってたからね｡
I was hoping for another natural childbirth.
おっにっぎっりっ｡
Onigiri!
あさってには うちの両親が
来てくれるんだけど…｡
In two days, my parents will be here...
あっ コラ ふうちゃん！
H-Hey, Fu!
Honestly...
あ…あ～もしもし｡ごめん｡
Oh, hello?
Sorry...
おにぎり ふえましたっ｡
More onigiri!
パパのとぉ ママのとぉ
フーカのとぉ あんちゃんの！
One for Daddy.
One for Mommy.
One for Fuuka.
One for An!
I need to talk to both of you.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)２人に話があるんだが…➡
外の空気でも吸いながら どうだ？
Why don't we get some fresh air?
I-It's cold out here.
さっ 寒いな 外｡やっぱり戻る？
Shall we go back inside?
あ いやっ 大丈夫ですよ｡
中は騒がしいんで｡
No, it's okay.
There's a lot of noise inside.
まあ本当なら 白ヒゲつけて➡
To be honest,
I'd have liked to have had a white mustache and red suit to give you the news...
赤白のコスチュームでも
着てから伝えたいところだが…｡
ちょいと早めの
クリスマスプレゼントだ➡
Consider this an early Christmas present.
君達のミッションが
正式に決定した｡
You've been officially assigned to a mission.
Quick, quick, slow. Quick, quick, slow.
クイック クイック スロー｡
Quick, quick, slow.
南波さん ここ後ろです！
あっ はい！
Nanba, we're supposed to step back.
Oh, okay.
右 左 左 右｡
Right, left, left, right.
ムッちゃん
足 もつれてるぞ～ははっ｡
Mu, you're gonna trip over yourself.
《ああ～なんという幸せ～》
This is pure bliss...
《よかった～！この世に
ダンスというものがあって！》
I'm so grateful to whoever invented dance!
I'll be sending an e-mail with more details,
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)詳細は後ほどメールするが
まあ大体そういうことだ｡➡
but here's a quick summary.
ベテランが１人 中堅が１人
そして君達 新人が２人…｡
One veteran, one expert...
And two rookies, you guys.
４人のクルーで
このミッションは挑んでもらう｡
This mission will have a four-person crew.
《この時 まるで僕は
生まれ変わったような…➡
At that moment, it was like I'd been reborn.
Or I should say...
あるいは 宇宙飛行士の自分が
ようやく生まれたような…➡
Like I had finally become an astronaut.
そんな気がしていた》
That was how it felt.
Hello?
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)もしもし…あ 俺だけど｡
Yeah, it's me.
Yeah.
実はさ さっき やっと
ミッションの内容が➡
Actually, I finally found out about the mission I've been assigned to.
明らかになったんだよ｡そう！
Yep.
本当！やったね｡どんな内容なの？
Really? That's great.
What will you be doing?
帰ったら話すよ｡
｢発表前だから 身内以外には➡
I'll tell you when I get home.
The mission hasn't been announced yet, so we're only allowed to tell family.
まだ知られないように｣ってさ｡
お楽しみに｡
I think you'll be excited.
(ユキ)わかった｡ん…んっ ん…｡
Okay...
Again...
さっきから
だんだん痛くなってきて…｡
The pain is increasing...
[ｹｲﾀｲ](ユキ)
多分これ…陣痛きたかも…｡
I think...
the contractions have started.
あ！いっ 今 タクシー呼ぶから
落ち着いて待ってて！
I-I'll call for a taxi!
Stay calm, and wait for me!
俺も すぐ向かうから！
[ｹｲﾀｲ](ユキ)うん…｡
I'll be right there...
Hello? This is an emergency! I need a taxi at the following address!
もしもし！至急１台お願いします｡
今から言う住所に！
こんな夜に ごめんなさい
こまち
小町さん｡
Sorry to bother you this late at night, Komachi...
(小町)かまへん かまへん｡
It's no big deal!
朝まで寝てると思いますけど
風佳をよろしくお願いします｡
I doubt she'll wake up until tomorrow, but could you please look after Fuuka?
I've got it.
(小町)まかしときぃ！
元気な赤ちゃん産んどいでぇ～！
Go have yourself a healthy baby!
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)予定より早くきたな｡
She's early...
しばらく この部屋で待っててね｡
あ はい｡
For now, please wait in this room.
Okay.
しんどいか？ユキ｡
Does it hurt, Yuki?
《うわあ～
どうすりゃいいんだろ…》
What should I do?
《辛そうだな…➡
It seems like a lot of pain...
眉間のシワが
こんなにくっきり…》
Her brow is all wrinkled...
《どこ こすってんのよ～➡
Why is he rubbing me there?
Why doesn't he rub my back instead?
どうせなら
腰とか さすってよ！》
(ユキ)ハァ ハァ…｡
フゥ フゥ…｡
(ユキ)フゥ フゥ フゥ…｡
何か 音楽でも聴く？
うん…いいね｡
Do you want to listen to some music?
Yeah, that'd be nice...
フゥ フゥ…｡
(ユキ)フゥ フゥ…｡
おぎゃあ おぎゃあ おぎゃあ｡
もう１枚！今度は上からね！
One more shot!
From above this time!
せ 先生！落ちないで下さいね｡
D-Doctor... You're gonna fall!
(医師)ヒューストンってね
ヒューストンだけにね｡
Give me a "Houston"...
In Houston!
It's a healthy baby girl!
(医師)元気な女の子で～す｡
おっ！おっ…｡よっ！
先生っ！
Doctor!
じゃあ これ｡
ありがとうございました 先生｡
Here you go.
Thank you so much, doctor!
Nah, your wife and baby did all the hard work.
いやいや 頑張ったのは
奥さんと赤ちゃんね｡
ありがとうございます｡
Thank you very much!
やっぱり 風佳の言ってた
“あん"ちゃんがいいかな 名前…｡
Do we go with An like Fuuka suggested?
そうね…｡
I think so.
ねえ そういえば 決まった
ミッションって何だったの？
Oh, didn't you say something about being assigned to a mission?
Right... I completely forgot.
あっ！そうだ 完全に忘れてた！
行き先が決まったんだ｡
どこだと思う？
I know my destination.
Guess where I'm going.
え？どこって
アイエスエス
月かＩＳＳか どっちかじゃ…｡
Huh? It's either the moon or the ISS, right?
いや…これ見て｡
Nope, look at this.
⦅君達クルーのミッションは…➡
Your crew has been assigned the mission
人類初となる有人小惑星探査だ⦆
of becoming the first humans to explore an asteroid.
小惑星!?
そう！
An asteroid?
Yes... We'll be going beyond the moon!
月より さらに先に行くんだよ！
すごい…あっ｡
That's amazing!
ねえ これ見た？
Hey, did you see this?
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)こりゃ 決まりだな…｡
Looks like...
we have a name.
(風佳)わあ～ ちっちゃ～い！
Wow! She's tiny!
あんちゃ～ん
おね～ちゃんですよ～！
An, I'm your sister!
あん
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)《安が生まれて僕は➡
With An's birth,
人生初の…
２人の娘の父になった｡➡
I became the father of two daughters for the first time in my life.
小惑星を目指す宇宙飛行士であり
２人の娘の父であり…》
I am an astronaut headed for an asteroid. And a father of two daughters.
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)《僕もまだ…
生まれたばっかだ…》
I'm just getting started!
The starlight illuminates my future, it's wow... truth
It's 3 AM, and I dream awake
With no idea of my future
only impatience consumes me
I have a thorn in my heart that won't allow me to lose to him
I'm walking a path of thorns I made for myself
But I won't forget the love I found
And I won't forget the ones close to me
I realized you cannot live your life alone
The starlight illuminates my future, and we are all shooting stars
My holy wishes turn all our sad lies into something better
Our orbits have gotten separated,
but I'm fine if you are close
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#97 Won't Go Away
As I move on to the next stage of my Houston training,
＜ヒューストンで
私の新たな訓練が進む中➡
家族で年越しをすることに＞
our family spends New Year's together.
Hibito is faced with a harsh reality.
＜日々人は 厳しい現実を
目の当たりにしていた＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Won't Go Away"